so the curious thing is that it generates a new board for every move and then for every successive move thereafter UNTIL there are no more moves to make (either there has been a win, loss or draw)
and only then, at those end states, does it calculate the score
and that score will be assigned to the most immediate possible move, facilitating the choice for that immediate next move

http://neverstopbuilding.com/minimax